Guide to the Keith Henson's Papers relating to Project Xanadu, XOC, and Eric Drexler, 1977-1997 M1292
Stanford University. Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Keith Henson. Papers relating to Project Xanadu, XOC and Eric Drexler
1977-1997
M1292
Stanford University. Department of Special Collections and University Archives
6.0 Linear feet
The collection includes files from XOC, VHS tapes, and Drexler drafts and galley proofs.
Henson, Keith
Collection Scope and Content Summary
The collection includes files from XOC, VHS tapes, and Drexler drafts and galley proofs.
Biography
Keith Henson and his wife Arel Lucas founded XOC (Xanadu Operating Company).
Acquisition Information
Gift of Arel Lucas, 2001 and 2002.
Access
The Media materials require at least two weeks advance notice to use in order to allow staff time to have use copies made from the original items.
Drexler, K. Eric.; Lucas, Arel; Nelson, Theodor H.; Xanadu Operating Company (XOC); Electronic publishing.; Hypertext systems.; Microcomputers--Programming.; Nanotechnology.; Self-publishing--Dataprocessing.; Technological innovations.; Videorecordings.; Word processing.
- Hibbert Related, X tech log, Files listing, ENT, TN-XOC-Memos, Works & Editions, Compare/Merge Algorithm, (blank), SCI, Powerbook, Task lists, Memex Doe, Drexler on Enfilade 10/88, Mark M's NanoTalk, 88.2 backend Semantics, Docs & links Presentation, Old documentation, Doc Plan, X-HBug DB, Bugs, Garbage Collection Docs and System Architecture Drawings (Box 1)
- Cornerstone, Key KO's, Xanadu Materials, Perfomance Testing, ACM Press Software Engineering Notes, Design Notes, Conextions & Cummins-Allison, Printer, UU Net, UUCP Map, Menex Demo Spec and Parc Place Systems. (Box 2)
- Bootstrap, Sun, Sun Software, Sun Catalyst, CPSR, Tapestry, Parc Place Systems, RX Project, Folio,Demo, Admin/Doc, SW/Microsoft/Windows NT, ADMIN, Management, Xanadu, Mike Butler, Rohart Bell, QA and Server HW (Box 3)
- XOC, Comerica Statements, Chris Hibbert Xanadu, Presentation Slides, Scematics, Febe Protocol 88.lx Documentation and Wired June 1995 (2 copies-one CDP) (Box 4)
- Xanadu, Performance Claims, Xanadu Handouts, Time & Exp, Tony Smith - "Why the Web?" and Misc. notes and papers. (Box 5)
- Dream Machines/Computer Lib Ted Nelson 1974 (first edition), "Hacker" The Computer Crime Card Game, XOC Business Cards, XOC Stamp (2), Fe, Memex, (blank) Xanadu FCS and Hypertext '89 Proceedings. (Box 6)
- VHS tapes: 4/27/93 Canopy schemes #1 MM,DT,CH,RP master, 4/27/93 Canopy schemes #2 MM,DT,CH,RP master, 4/30/93 Extend Storage Format Ravi, Dean, Mark, ENT BUNS - Mark M, Chris H, Calvin Ward, Dick Gruen, Mike B. Part 1 5/3/93, 5/4/93 High-level-BeBe Ravi, Mark, Dean, 5/6/93 Worm issues Mark, Dean, Ravi, Error Handling Strategies Part 1 Mark M. vs. Dean + Mike B & Carl 5/20/93 (LP), Architecture for Mike B, + Error Handling Strategies Mark M, Dean, Mike B, Carl 5/20/93 (LP), Mark M + Chris 5/25/93 1 of figuring out complexity measures for placeholder indexes, Propogation of endorsement + Recorders through volume, Mark M + Chris 5/25/93 2 of 2 complexity measures for Ent usage Rob J on FE, Rob J on Front End 5/25/93 and Mark Miller Demo 3 Promis System (Box 7)
  Conditions Governing Access note
  The Media materials require at least two weeks advance notice to use in order to allow staff time to have use copies made from the original items.
- Miscellaneous files, binders, stationary, etc.: Cancelled checks, Odesta Corp Double Helix Users Guide, Odesta Corp Double Helix Reference Guide, Xanadu Back End and Spire Interface Doe, Literary Machines 93.1 Theodor Holm Nelson, XOC Inc., Literary Machines 1981 Theodor Hoim Nelson, XOC Inc., Future Presentations logo, Group Photo, Index box - ref. Cards, Home Computer Revolution Ted Nelson 1977 (autographed) and 1 box Xanadu stationary. (Carton 8)
- Drexler materials (related): Engines of Creation K. Eric Drexler 1986 Anchor Press (autographed), Cryonics Volume 9(8), August 1988, draft "The Future by Design" Drexler, draft "Molecular Nanotechnology: Molecular Machinery and Manufacturing" Drexler 1991, draft "Nanosystems Molecular Machinery, Manufacturing, and Computation" Drexier 1991 and galley proofs "Engines of Creation" Drexler., 1988-1991 (Box 9)
- Accession MSS.2002-281: Memex Business Plan December 1997; Memex folders and notebook; Xanadu programing binder;Cassette Tapes Drexler 2-7,9 unlabled;1 group photo; Drexler file, newspaper clipping "Remembering Home Brew Computer Club" (Box 10)
- Born-Digital Materials, 3.554 gigabytes
  Scope and Contents
  Six hard drives were received with this collection. Forensic disk images were created in-house for hard drives CM01 and CM02. Hard drives CM03, CM04, CM05 and CM06 could not be imaged in-house due to electronic and mechanical problems. They were sent to Data Recovery Services Inc. for data extraction. The original hard drives are not available, however, the contents of the hard drives can be access at http:\\XXXXXX.
  - CM01, 1.0 computer media hard drive (Carton 11)
  - CM02, 1.0 computer media Hard drive (Carton 11)
  - CM03 (Carton 11)